How State is Set
Earlier in this lesson, we saw how we can define a component's state at the time of initialization. Since state reflects mutable information that ultimately affects rendered output, a component may also update its state throughout its lifecycle using this.setState(). As we've learned, when local state changes, React will trigger a re-render of the component.

There are two ways to use setState(). The first is to merge state updates. Consider a snippet of the following component:

class Email extends React.Component {
 state = {
   subject: '',
   message: ''
 }
 // ...
});
Though the initial state of this component contains two properties (subject and message), they can be updated independently. For example:

this.setState({
 subject: 'Hello! This is a new subject'
})
This way, we can leave this.state.message as-is, but replace this.state.subject with a new value.

The second way we can use setState() is by passing in a function rather than an object. For example:

this.setState((prevState) => ({
 count: prevState.count + 1
}))
Here, the function passed in takes a single prevState argument. When a component's new state depends on the previous state (i.e., we are incrementing count in the previous state by 1), we want to use the functional setState().


s
QUIZ QUESTION
What is true about setting state in our components? Please check all that apply:

Whenever setState() is called, the component also calls render() with the new state

State updates can be merged by passing in an object to setState()



State updates can be asynchronous (i.e., setState() can accept a function with the previous state as its first argument)



